<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Unicycle Football</string>
    <string name="stats">Stats</string>
    <string name="title_activity_stats">statsActivity</string>
    <string name="statsButton">Stats Go</string>
    <string name="teamButton">Team Go</string>
    <string name="schedButton">Schedule Go</string>
    <string name="title_activity_schedule">scheduleActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_team">teamActivity</string>
    <string name="uflLogoText">"Unicycle Football League"</string>

    <string-array name="teams_array">
        <item>Blackouts</item>
        <item>Beardos</item>
        <item>Chupacabras</item>
        <item>Gnarwhals</item>
        <item>Hotdogs</item>
        <item>Unicychos</item>
        <item>Unicorns</item>
        <item>WildHogs</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_blackouts">blackoutsActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "THE FIELD
X-1 Playing field sizes will vary since not all parking-lots are the same. All fields are treated as 100 unit fields and penalties, touch-backs, gains, and losses of units are based on percentage. The percentages are verbalized as units. (UFL units lengths will vary) The first down chains can be modified in length for best “10 UFL units” to match the field of play.
X-1.2 The distance for a first down can be adjusted to a length that best suits the field and players.
X-2 Games are free for spectators. If this changes into a cheap admission priced event, clowns always get in free, no exceptions!
X-3 The number of players can vary from 4 to 11 on each team. 5 or more is preferred. The field size will sometimes limit the amount of players on the field.
SAFETY REQUIREMENTS
Z-1 Bike helmets are required during game play. No helmet, no play.
Z-2 No Kevlar helmets. These are the bullet proof ones the military uses. They will hurt people who are struck by them.
Z-3 NO SPEARING!!! This means no plowing your head into an opponent. This will break your damn neck, and tack on a 15 unit penalty plus loss of down!
Z-4 THIS IS FLACKLE FOOTBALL! A person with the ball may be tackled by removing their flags during play. A player may also be tackled by a technique referred too as, “the least amount of force required to cause the ball handler to dismount their unicycle.” This definitions implies a “sliding scale of force” may be used to dismount a ball handler on a need too basis only. Any shove, push, hit deemed excessive could result in a minimum punishment of a 15 unit penalty or up to a maximum of removal from the league. The referees can implement this rule up to the maximum of removal of the violator from the game. The league coordinator can decide whether further suspension is necessary.
Z-5 If a player jumps vertical off their unicycle, it is illegal to make contact other than a flag pull if the player is in the air.
THE JOUST
J-1 A player from each team uses the “multipurpose-use UFL stick” to joust.
J-2 If the “multipurpose-use UFL stick” is dropped during the joust, the joust continues until a rider is dismounted from their unicycle.
J-3 The winner of the joust chooses whether their team kicks or receives the ball in the initial kick-off of the game.
J-4 The team that is elected to kick-off gets to chose which end zone they will defend.
J-5 If a player strikes the opponent in the face with the multipurpose-use UFL stick, they lose the joust and there will be a 15 unit penalty to the team in violation after the Kick-off.
THE KICK OFF
K-1 A kick-off occurs at the beginning of each half, after a scored touchdown or after a field goal. (STD)
K-2 To kick off the ball, a player kicks the ball from the 30 unit line of their end of the field to the opposing team. When the ball is “kicked”, after it passed the 50 unit line, the ball can be recovered by either team.
K-2.5 It is permissible for a receiving team player to catch the ball off of their unicycle. If the receiving player is merely touched by a kick-off defender, the play is dead and the ball is spotted at the greatest point of disadvantage. (See FU-2)
K-3 A kick-returnee may “fair catch” a kicked ball by waving his hand toward the sky. If the ball is caught successfully after a “fair catch” is signaled, the ball is down where he/she caught it and the player may not be touched by the kicking team. If a fair catch occurs in the end-zone, a “touch-back” will result. If the fair catcher is touched after the signal, the ball will be spotted 15 units forward from the fair catch.
K-4 When the ball lies in the end-zone after a kick, the kick-returning team may “kneel” the ball by laying their unicycle wheel over the ball.
K-5 If the ball is untouched and lies in the end-zone and is recovered by the kicking team, a touchdown occurs and the ball is kicked again.
K-6 If the ball is “kicked” out of bounds before the end zone, the ball is spotted on the 40 unit line.
K-7 If the ball is “kicked” and travels out of the end zone untouched by a player, the ball is spotted at the 20 yard line.
K-8 If the ball travels out of the end zone after being touched by the receiving team’s player, a touchback results.
THE PUNT
P-1 When a team reaches 4th down, they have the option to attempt conversion of that down, kick a field goal, or punt.
P-1.3 When a team elects to punt the ball by foot, they are allowed to fake punt for a chance to convert on downs. The ball must be hiked to the punter for a punt from foot to occur.
P-2 The punt is made from the line of scrimmage by the team that fails to convert the down.
P-3 Once a team chooses to punt, they may not attempt to convert the 4th down.
P-3.1 A punt can be made by kicking the ball down field from the line of scrimmage to the opposing team.
P-4 A punt consists of a player “punting” the ball to the opposing team, similar to a kick-off.
P-5 If the “punted” ball travels out of bounds before the end zone, and it was punted from the foot, the ball is spotted at that corresponding unit line for which it went out.
P-6 The “punted” ball cannot be recovered by the punting team unless it touches a player from the receiving team first.
THE FIELD GOAL
F-1 A field goal can be kicked by a team on offense that has a down remaining. A field-goal can be attempted on any down during a drive, or series of downs.
*At any point, the offense may opt to kick a field goal for 3 points. If the field goal is successful, it will be followed by a kick-off from the scoring team. If the field goal is unsatisfactory, the defensive team will attain possession from the line of scrimmage.
F-2 To kick the ball successfully, the team kicking must hike the ball to the “kicker” and he/she must punt the ball off the unicycle through the “Field Goal Foxes”. (Equivalent to uprights in pedestrian football)
F-3 The “field goal foxes” are the width of 3 people(arms extended and linked) The ball must pass through or above the shoulders or into the face of the center field goal fox for a field-goal to be successful.
F-4 The “kicker” must “punt” the ball off the unicycle. The kicker is not required to mount the unicycle before the hike.
F-5 When defending a field goal, a player may not make contact with the kicker unless he /she makes contact with the ball first. This is penalized by 10 units and a first down.
THE ROSTER
R-1 Teams can only have nine members on their roster. Team rosters need to be submitted before teams can play. Any player that is not on a roster has the option to join any team that does not have nine on their roster. The only team that can have more than nine on their roster would be a first year team.
R-2 Any player that hasn't played for half of the season with their respective team may be vetoed from play by the opposing team during playoffs.
Game Play
OFFENSE
*The offense’s job is to get the ball in the end-zone. A well rounded offense will run and pass the ball successfully.
O-1 A player is in play only when he/she is on the unicycle.
O-2 After a “kickoff” and the field position is established, the offensive team is awarded four downs to score an STD, a field goal or attain a new set of downs.
O-3 Scored Touch Down (STD)- the ball must cross the goal line while in possession of a player on a unicycle or be caught by a player on a unicycle.
O-4 Six points are awarded to a team who gets an STD. An optional one or two point conversion may then be attempted.
- One Point Conversion- from the 3 unit line, the ball may be thrown or rushed (ridden on unicycle) into the end zone.
-Two Point Conversion- from the 3 unit line, the ball may be kicked from the unicycle through the field goal foxes.
O-5 A field goal for 3 points may be attempted. refer to F-1
O-6 A new set of downs is awarded to a team for rushing the ball or receiving the ball beyond the first down marker. This marker is measured by a rope tied to the multi-purpose use UFL sticks. The distance to achieve a first down may be extended by moving the line of scrimmage back for penalties, QB sacks, and tackles behind the line of scrimmage.
O-7 One eligible receiver is allowed to be in motion before the ball is hiked. A player in motion can travel parallel too, or backwards from the L.O.S. A receiver may not advance forward before the hike. (false start)
O-8 A ball carrier must remain balanced on his/her unicycle to remain in play. If he/she “dabs” (toe, or foot touches the ground) or if they fall off the unicycle they are down and the ball is spotted where the ball was at the the dab or dismount.
O-9 If a player falls off their unicycle and does not have possession of the ball, they can remount the unicycle and resume their play status by rolling forward or backward one full revolution. (HOT LAVA RULE)
If a player remounts their unicycle but fails to roll forward one full revolution, and he/she makes a tackle or flag pull, a 10 unit penalty will be tacked on.
POSITIONS ON OFFENSE
Center is one of the most challenging positions in the game. A good center can hike the ball while mounting a unicycle and block the pass rush all at the same time!
C-7 The “center” must line up at the line of scrimmage every down. The center is responsible for hiking the ball and blocking defensive players from tackling offensive players behind the line of scrimmage (L.O.S.) (blocking described later)
C-7.1 The center is an ineligible receiver. Passing the ball to an ineligible receiver is penalized by a 5 unit loss and loss of down.
C-7.2 The “center” can catch a ball that has been tipped by the defense and they can recover a fumble.
C-7.3 The “center” must hike the ball simultaneously to mounting their unicycle. The “center” must not mount the unicycle until the “trigger hut” is called by the QB.
Quarterbacks are the central nervous system of the offensive unit. If the QB is having a bad day, so is their offense.
Q-8 The “Quarterback”, (QB) Usually lines up behind the “center”. The QB can line up anywhere except on the line of scrimmage.
Q-8.5 * The QB initiates a play by saying, “hut”. This “hut” can be repeated up to 4 times as an attempt to lure the defense off-sides. The “hut” that the offense initiates their play on is referred to as the “trigger hut”. The QB must not move anything but his/her lips on “huts” that are not the trigger hut” If the QB violates this rule, a “false start” penalty is called, resulting in a 5 unit loss and repeat of the down.
Q-9 The QB may be fully mounted on their unicycle when they take a hike. During a hard count, the QB must take the hike simultaneously to mounting the unicycle. (helps ref interpret false start)
Q-10 If the hike to the QB is dropped or missed, a fumble occurs. (see Fu-1)
Q-11 If the QB pitch or laterals the ball backwards or parallel to an eligible receiver and it is dropped or hits the ground, a fumble results. (see Fu-1)
Q-12 The QB may throw, lob, toss, chuck, or heave a ball forward to an eligible receiver before or after the receiver crosses the L.O.S. If the pass is not caught successfully, an incomplete pass occurs and the “game clock” is stopped.
Q-13 The QB cannot throw the ball forward once they’ve crossed the L.O.S.
Q-14 If a ball is lateraled to an eligible receiver, and the receiver laterals it back to the QB, the QB may then throw the ball forward provided he/she has not crossed the L.O.S.
Q-15 The QB is an eligible receiver and may “rush” (advance forward on the unicycle) the ball.
Wide-Receivers specialize in hauling unicycle-ass and catching anything thrown their direction. They hate corner-backs.
WR-1 Wide receivers may line up, off or on the L.O.S.
WR-1.2 A Wide-Receiver is an eligible receiver, and may rush the ball and block too.
WR-2 Receiver’s can block defensive players behind the L.O.S. and up to 3 yards beyond the L.O.S. while the ball is on the ground behind the L.O.S.
WR-3 A receiver can block anywhere on the field once the ball has advanced beyond the L.O.S.
WR-4 A pass to a receiver is considered complete if he/she catches it with “ball control” before dismounting their unicycle.
WR-5 A pass cannot be completed to a receiver who is out-of-bounds or has traveled out of bounds during that play.
Half-backs protect the QB from anybody that slips through the offensive-line. Occasionally a halfback will take a hand-off or even catch the ball down field.
HB-1 Halfbacks can line up on or off the L.O.S. (Rules for the half-back are identical to the WR.)
DEFENSE
The defensive unit strives to shutdown the opposing offense. A good defense is arguably more important than a good offense.
D-1 A defensive player is only in play if they are mounted on their unicycle.

CLOCK RULES
1. Clock starts on the kickoff only when it touches a player on their unicycle. If it goes out of bounds or is picked up by a player off the unicycle, it does not start.
2. Clock stops on a first down.
3. Clock stops on an incomplete pass.
4.Clock stops on a player running out of bounds with the ball.
5. Clock stops on a touchdowns or field goal.
6. Clock always stops after a 4th down if the team does not get a first down. This is called “turn over on downs”.
7. Clock stops on a play with a penalty after the play is dead.
8. Clock stops on a timeout and each team only gets three. The referee determines how many have been used. A referee can negate a timeout if it was called by a dumbass that didn’t need to call one because the clock was already stopped.
9. The clock does not stop on a running play that end inbounds and is not a first down.
10. The clock does not start on an extra point kick attempt of any kind.
11. The clock starts with 13 minutes.
12. UFL will not observe the 2 minute warning timeout but the time keeper should yell at the refs when it reaches 2 minutes left in the half.

Penalties
KICKOFFS
Kickoffs are at the fourth parking spot.
If the kickoff goes out of bounds, it goes to the sixth parking spot.
If the kickoff goes out of the end zone, it goes to the third parking spot.
If a safety occurs, the team then punts from the sixth parking spot. There are no onsides kicks on a safety punt.
Onside kicks must pass the 50 and touch the ground or a player before they are considered a free ball.
FUMBLES AND PEDESTRIAN RECOVERY:
In a loose ball situation, the spot goes to the point of least advantage which is usually where they left their unicycle.
OFFSIDES:
5 units and repeat down
HOLDING:
Defensive penalty: 10 units and automatic first down.
Offensive penalty: 10 units and repeat down.
BLOCK IN BACK accidental:
Defensive penalty: 10 units and automatic first down.
Offensive penalty: 10 units and repeat down.
BLOCK IN BACK non-accidental:
Defensive penalty: 15 units and automatic first down.
Offensive penalty: 15 units and loss of down.
PASS INTERFERENCE:
Defensive penalty: Spot foul and first down.
Offensive penalty: 10 units and repeat down.
ILLEGAL PROCEDURE is 5 units and repeat down:
Quarterback doing fake hike.
Center not mounting.
Two men in motion.
Too many men on the field.
Missing the ball on when trying to kick off.
Moving forward instead of parallel when in motion.
Passing to the center.
Nose Guard not lining up on center.
Improper quickstart: "They can take two steps and must be behind the line of
scrimmage when they mount."
Quarterback making forward progress before the hike. "They can mount but not
start pedaling until the hike."
INDECENT TOUCHING "foot on ground tackle or block" accidental:
Defensive penalty: 10 units and automatic first down.
Offensive penalty: 10 units and repeat down.
INDECENT TOUCHING non-accidental:
Defensive penalty: 15 units and automatic first down.
Offensive penalty: 15 units and loss of down.
DELAY OF GAME: 5 units and repeat down if team does not hike the ball or take the field 15 seconds after whistle blow.
DELAY OF GAME Big Baby: 5 units if throwing or kicking the ball excessively far after a play. Basically if someone gets pissed and kicks the ball way off the field or down field so someone has to chase it.
UNNECESSARY ROUGHNESS: 15 units and automatic first down or 15 units and loss of down.
1st offense per player: warning
2nd offense per player: optional half-time suspension from game.
3rd offense per player: automatic suspension for half and optional game suspension.
4th offense per player: automatic game suspension.
UNSPORTSMANLIKE CONDUCT: Fighting or purposely trying to injure another player. Half-time suspension or full game. Depending on severity.
KICKING OUT WITH INTENT: It is hard to gauge when someone kicks out their unicycle to block another player. However, if you are going to call it, try to call it the same as "indecent touching" 10 units and a bad one as unnecessary roughness 15 units."
    </string>
    <string name="Standings">
        "
        1]Gnarwhals    8 - 0
        2]Bierdos      7 - 1
        3]Hotdogs      4 - 4
        4]Unicorns     3 - 5
        4]Blackouts    3 - 5
        6]Unicychos    2 - 6
        7]Chupacabras  0 - 8"
    </string>
    <string name="title_schedule">Schedule</string>
    <string name="title_teams">Teams</string>
    <string name="title_stats">Stats</string>
    <string name="title_ruleBook">RuleBook</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Action</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rule_page"> Rules </string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
</resources>


